如果委員想發問，
二零一九年第七十六號法律公告。
啊！代表進入我哋嘅會議室。
而被嘅標明修訂文本。
同埋咧，就香港國際仲裁中心發出嘅立法會參考資料摘要。
檔案編號係L P十九足零零足四C。
已經有足夠嘅法定人數，而家我正式宣佈開會。
文件編號係C B括弧四九六三十八-hi-fen十九括弧零一號文件。
另外咧就係L.S.七十三short十八-hyphen十九號文件，係法律事務部報告。
咁今日嘅啊會議相關嘅文件咧，係啊派咗畀大家，就係啊。
主席可邀請香港仲裁中心，噉我哋而家咧，首先咧就係希望仲裁中心嘅誒。
法律事務部就二零一九年仲裁委任仲裁員及調解員決定嘅修訂規則。
關於二零一九年仲裁豁免委任仲裁員及調解員和決定仲裁員人數嘅修訂規則。
我哋可以啊，而家就試試，因為咧，我哋人數唔算多啦，咁所以可能都會畀足夠嘅時間畀大家嘅。
我提醒各位委員，要披露任何與二零一九年仲裁委任仲裁員及調解員和決定仲裁員人數修訂規則有關嘅直接或間接金錢利益。
噉我哋係會逐項審議條文嘅，嚇，亦都係咧就係啊小組委員會如果完成研究有關規則嘅政策之後咧，我哋咧就會係逐條審議。
係。
好。
我知道。
工作中心緊張。
Are you going to speak?
係，委員，如果有人想。
Thank you very much.
即係聽日可以討論嘅。
嘅秘書長啊，Miss Sarah Grima。
O.K.好，咁咧就誒，我諗我哋咧就係誒正式。
誒，我第一陣先嚇，我都要問一問啊，秘書先。我哋如果延展嘅呢個嘅討論。
就會係最遲聽日進入會務討作出討論㗎。係即係，只不過係你噉。
啊！並且要同大家宣佈咧，就係根據委員喺上次會議商定，我作為小組委員會主席。
誒，劉橋先生同埋李天恩政策專員係誒，睇下邊一位係咪Miss Sarah Glima？
將會喺聽日六月五號立法會會議上動議將規則嘅審議期延展至二零一九年七月十號。
waive the fee in in certain cases.
There are three other proposed amendments that are primarily technical in nature.
That our equivalent HKIC may move ahead and make a decision, and we would move that.
I'm sorry, I didn't. I didn't hear the translation of your introduction, so.
The third amendment that we are moving is that the
第一是，H.K.I.A.C.有能力 amend 任何的時間限制，那目前適用於規則。
在一些案件，會似乎適宜HKIC有權豁免那筆費用，對於案件的爭議金額較小，例如。
I will introduce the proposed amendments. Yes, briefly, briefly, very briefly. After your introduction, we would go through the regulation.
That be a discretionary decision to allow us more flexibility in terms of situations where it may not be appropriate for us to move forward and make a decision.
This can be important, for example, where a party has not complied with the current time limits and, for example, requests an extension. This is very normal in how we operate under our rules, and really is a matter of our internal process.
at the moment, for a party to an arbitration to request a decision from HKIAC, HKIAC must charge a fee of Hong Kong dollars eight thousand for any request.
The provision with respect to the delivery of documents or the service of documents under the Cap 609C be amended to align with the delivery of documents under the Hong Kong Arbitration Ordinance. At the moment, that is not compatible.
那係，我們想插入一個新規則，第13/2A，根據這個規則，HKIAC有權豁免任何申請人根據《香港仲裁條例》作出裁決時所須繳付的費用。
provision by provision, yeah. Okay, understood. Well, thank you very much. The proposed amendments that the HKIAC is seeking to introduce for Cap Six Hundred and Nine C fall into four main categories, but there is one main amendment that has motivated the proposed amendments.
誒，宣佈會議開始。宣佈會議開始之前，我自己都要誒陳述啦。我都係誒有做仲裁嘅工作，亦都係誒有做仲裁員嘅工作嘅。咁呢一度咧就係簡單説明一下。誒，而家咧我哋就請誒香港國際仲裁中心。
和，what we find in our experience under our cases is that we have, for example, one dispute where more than one decision is required from HKIAC and the party moving for the decision is required to make two payments of 8,000 Hong Kong dollars. So we would be seeking to have the power to
係。
no，it's a one-off fee。
understand what we have been, yeah.
那係個總結，係四個主要嘅建議修訂。
Our powers under the ordinance are only applicable where Hong Kong is the seat of arbitration.
嚇，定係有有案件嗰個range嗰個嗰個誒數額嘅分別㗎？
correct，the eight thousand Hong Kong dollars applies to all cases，no matter what the amount in dispute is。
That is correct, and it would also be an incentive for parties to opt for Hong Kong as the seat of arbitration.
咁咧就誒嗰個八千蚊就係誒一次，即係每次而家最基本收八千蚊嘅係嘛？最基本嘅費用嚟嘅。
O.K.嗯，咁咧就誒，我哋誒而家現時呢一部分咧，都係喺政策上嘅，睇下委員有冇問題。
first of all decide the number of arbitrators and then come back and and request the appointment of an arbitrator. In that scenario, they would have to pay the fee twice.
即係每一次有一個決定就要畀八千蚊，誒唔根據嗰個案嘅一個誒誒牽涉到嘅數額嘅，因為我記得有時我哋做嗰啲都幾貴幾貴嘅，佢係幾十億嗰啲誒商業嘅紛爭，其實佢都係同樣嘅收費嘅。
咁即係話，如果而家你哋有酌情權去豁免咧，就其實亦都可以令到一啲面額更細嘅案件咧，係被吸引佢可以誒，即係都選擇我哋香港嘅仲裁嘅中心作為紛爭解決嘅一個選擇。
The final amendment that we are proposing is that HKIAC have the discretion to make a decision after the expiry of certain time limits. At the moment, in two places in Cap 609C, it is provided that HKIAC must proceed to make a decision. In two other places, there are.
啊，或者咧，我自己都想問清楚少少嘅啫。誒，好多謝阿誒Miss誒Grima頭先嘅簡介啦。咁咧就頭先你提到咧就係話嗰個可以有權力去豁免誒八千蚊嗱，因為我希望誒Miss Grima誒或者其他嘉賓都誒代表都理解。
係啦，我哋希望公眾咧能夠跟進我哋嘅討論，所以咧我都會盡量係會用誒廣東話，都起碼大家聽會嘅時候咧就會知道我哋討論緊嘅重點嚇。咁所以可能誒一定要聽嗰個耳機，you might need to rely on the S I啊， to
香港 much more attractive.
所以， first and foremostly， it would be a benefit to Hong Kong as the seat.
some of the feedback that we have received over several years now is that.
誒通常係咪細到會唔會係得幾萬蚊到十幾萬噉樣？會唔會係呢啲咁細嘅數額？
因為 of the fact that we have to charge this fee, no matter the size of the case, when compared with say other venues that are popular for maritime arbitration, for example London.
誒，我想啊，Miss Grima又解釋下，或者其他都可以補充嘅，係係誒，係咪因為海事仲裁通常又係數額係比較細啊？
咁所以嗰啲亦都可以，當然可以係好大面額，好大面額嘅，因為牽涉到保險，咁可能大家就會牽涉到賠償，究竟係邊度？咁香港其實我哋個海港係好活躍嘅。
It is true that this proposed amendment would benefit maritime arbitration and that it would make Hong Kong more attractive as a seat. One of the motivations behind this proposed amendment is feedback from the maritime arbitration community as well as the construction arbitration community.
我補充少少喺誒二零一五年咧，我係舉辦咗我自己有份舉辦嘅一個誒國際研討會喺啊，係講到一帶一路嗰陣時，亦都有一個新嘅思路係See係Water嗰個嚇。
係誒有一啲啊討論咧，就係話呢一個而家呢個修訂咧，係會對於海事仲裁，即係嗰個啊發展，即係攞咗海事仲裁業務（maritime arbitration）啊，亦都會係啊增加一個吸引力。
Under the ordinance, HKIC can make three decisions. We can appoint an arbitrator, we can decide on the number of arbitrators that the parties have to agree, and we can appoint a mediator. So a party can come to us asking for one of those decisions. In some cases, a party may need to come to us in the same case to take two decisions. For
the fee charged for appointing an arbitrator in London by the London Maritime Arbitration Association is lower than our fees, and so in order to make us more competitive and more attractive as a venue, then being able to waive the fees in certain types of cases in low cases where there is a low amount in dispute would make
咁咧就其中一個國際嘅專家都有提到咧，就係話啊，其實海面上咧誒，如果講緊一大誒嗰個誒即係sea belt啊嗰個海上嗰個嗰個途徑咧，就會有機會出現誒海盜嚇，即係真係會有人搶咗海上嘅貨啊噉樣。
數字。
Workers, international trade cases, and sometimes there's quite a lot of overlap between international trade and maritime cases.
可以有機會，正如我哋講，而家降低即係個收費可以免埋啦。我哋應該有機會會搶多幾多個case咧？唔知你哋會唔會有啲噉嘅估計嘅啫？嚇，即係唔知有冇係啦？唔該。會唔會有啲數字畀我哋參考咧？嗯。
啊，如果有近嘅紛爭，能夠我哋誒吸引到海事仲裁，係能夠由細係去到大，即係慢慢我哋可以有機會係準備好啲，我哋多啲呢啲專才咧。誒，我覺得係誒好事嚟嘅。噉我雖然我覺得可能係唔需要申報嘅，不過都會誒提及一下啦，因為成大咧。
係喺幾年前咧，有開到一個海事仲裁嘅研究中心嚇，噉係我啲同事去做嘅嚇。我係做商事仲裁嘅啫。噉我覺得，如果將來係可以係鼓勵多啲新嘅新嘅仲裁員，佢可以涉足海事仲裁，或者將來會有好大嘅面額嘅紛爭，係唔出奇咯。
嗰個發展，OK，噉我就見到啊，周浩鼎議員想問問題嘅，啊，請周浩鼎議員。係誒誒，唔該，主席。咁對於目前今次即係豁免呢個收費安排，都正如頭先Screamer都解釋啦，都係希望能夠可以增加我哋本身香港個本地嘅仲裁中心嗰個。
個誒競爭力噉，我相信呢個都冇爭議嘅，都係好希望做好件事啦。誒，我就想問下咧，因為頭先亦都聽到咧，關於個海事仲裁嗰方面咧，即係而家就誒頭先聽到就話，可能倫敦本身嘅收費都比我哋低嘅。咁而家我哋誒再積極啲啦，咁咁唔知有冇一啲？
啲啊，過去啊，你哋掌握嘅數據，即係比如話，可能喺倫敦本身一啲小額或者做嘅海事仲裁，佢哋嗰個case嘅數量大概係點？又或者我哋而家自己本身過去啊一段時間裏面誒喺你哋掌握到嘅數字裏面，我哋自己做海事仲裁嗰個大概嘅case。
嘅數量係幾多咧？誒呢個一個小問題啦。咁另外一樣嘢咧就係誒都係一個意見啫。咁而家因為高增值航運業咧，我自己本身就比較關注嘅。咁誒海事保險咧，政府就已經業回應咗業界訴求咧，就今年開始咧就減税。噉啊，亦都呢個咧係呼應。
翻我哋一路都希望咧，係成個高增值航運業咧，就正正包括船泊租任啊、船主啊、船東啊、誒誒海事保險啊，或者仲裁、仲裁就係啱啱而家我哋講緊啲節啦，能夠儘量吸引喺香港度做，或者佢哋喺呢度落户咧，噉啊可以成個產。
產業集羣咁形成咧，噉啊，如果做到咁咧，噉啊，真係有助於香港成個產業同就業個安排嘅。所以我就比較關心，即係唔知道可能同時會唔會有啲基本數據已經話畀我聽，即係過去嘅一段時間，我哋嘅海事仲裁機制係幾多，或者你哋可能預計啊，我哋同倫敦嘅比較未來係咪？
Of course, thank you very much. So every year, HKIAC administers between two hundred and fifty and three hundred arbitrations, and last year, fifteen point one per cent of those cases were maritime cases. So that gives you a sense of it's an important sector in our work, and also some of a large sector of our.
I don't have the specific figures for the London Maritime Arbitration Association, but they are much higher than ours. But they are also much higher than any international arbitral institution in the world. They really are the leaders. So they run into I think it's even into the thousands per year, but I would have to check that. So I think that.
What steps we can take, we should take to attract more of these cases to Hong Kong. And I'm glad that mention was made of the Belt and Road initiative, because the government's policy, of course, is that Hong Kong is a is a leading venue for dispute resolution for Belt and Road disputes, and we do see that reflected in our caseload. We've started to see some.
嗯。
誒，嚇！
and express power, so there is no issue.
在 practise， we do move out. we do
no discretion，即係以前係完全冇呢個酌情權，係延期噉。通常出現咩情況，我哋真係變咗冇得做啦。係遲點樣出現呢個問題？
may, if the circumstances of any particular case so justify, amend any of the time limits under the rules. Of course, that would not apply to time limits that the parties themselves have agreed upon, which we would we would be obliged to respect.
收唔到啦啊，或者有黑客收唔到啦噉，係需唔需要有合理嘅理由咧？定係就誒呢個算係誒差唔多必然嘅，有機會可以延期咧嚇？Thank you。
唔知可能spaming啊，又可能係太多啊，成lock資料，即係你全部用電郵啊嘛，咁好多文件十幾二十個，咁可能即係有啲都會係話係收唔到，咁即係話以前其實都有呢個酌情權嘅，而家就將佢明確。
得好，第三點啦。頭先講送達請求誒，現你話而家修改咗之後就會劃一誒，以前係唔符合唔符合乜嘢啊？我唔知有冇聽漏咗，所以我想你講清楚少少。
明即係即係現時咧，其實都有喺個別，如果佢有合理嘅解釋嘅情況底下咧，你哋都會容許嘅。因為我舊我以前做嘅一啲仲裁咧，的確就算用電油咧，都可能係話收唔到㗎。
海峽爭議出嚟，和也，我們有最高數量的案件，係中港中國公司和非中國公司，和那一直係HKIAC的標誌，和重要部分的案件，係在海事領域，所以那給你一種感覺。
好嚇，係好，周浩鼎議員。誒，我就係啦，咁唔該曬同事咧。咁至少我哋而家睇到，即係起碼我哋都有相當份額嘅誒數字，佔咗我哋所有嘅份額裏邊咧，都係做海事仲裁嘅。咁當然我哋都其實清楚知道咧，香港同同倫。
咧喺海事啊，maritime business方面，成個產業嚟講係好難比，因為佢哋真係而家全球嚟講，無論係海事保險啊、仲裁啊，或者所有嗰啲啊shipping finance嗰方面咧，都係領先嘅。咁好難話攞我哋香港即刻去同佢比較。不過誒，我同意咧，即係。
我哋都係以一個高嘅誒水平作為一個目標啦，希望我哋點都可以慢慢追上啦嚇。因為新加坡都係好喺呢方面好積極，咁所以我哋而家都怕落後啊，所以而家都要加緊咁去做。噉我諗我係呢個意見啫，冇其他㗎啦。唔該啊，主席。好啊，我我自己都有畀啲資料，我早早。
其應該九九五年已經係有協助，even內地上海啊、北京啊，佢哋係海事仲裁嗰啲啊工作嚇，同埋啊出版嘅宣傳嘅。咁所以我諗，我哋係加強啦。我哋自己啊一個幼苗咧，我相信係可以成長嘅，而香港嘅。
人才嘅實力嚇好誒嗱誒，我另外仲要想問清楚嘅，其實我想喺政策上了解咗咧，我諗我哋陣間逐項條文咧，其實就未必需要好花好多嘅時間，因為我哋都希望今日就可以搞掂曬佢嘅。如果我哋啊，所以你就啊好清楚簡短咧，我啊。
誒誒誒講咗畀我聽嗰個答案就可以㗎啦。誒第二個你提到嘅建議就係話時限嘅規定喺內部誒就而家經過呢個修訂就可以延期嘅，有噉嘅係咪內部有個權限？係咪未修定係唔可以啊？定係延即即係咪absolute？
We do act outside the strict time limits that are under the sub legislation at the moment, and so that's a matter of internal practice. And what we're seeking with the amendment is to make that express that that is not an issue, and that would mean that we would not have to face arguments from parties saying that that is within our power or not.
under the current sub legislation, what the time limit is that I'm specifically talking about is the fact that we must give the respondent party fourteen days to submit comments on any request. That is something that we always do. We must adhere to that. It may be, for example, that a request is served on a respondent and the respondent
Let's us know that it has only received the request say one day before it is required to make comments. In that situation, it is advisable to give the respondent more time to make their comments, which would then inform our decision. So that is what we are already doing. But this amendment is seeking to make that.
係咪？亦都可能係咪？現在明確呢個延期可以批准延期嘅酌情權，需唔需要有合理嘅即係理由咧？即係好似我剛才講，我哋有好多電郵嘅往來，但係文件量太多，有時都塞咗，即係即係直情啊塞咗車啦！喺喺電郵係。
Thank you. To be clear, in the current sub legislation, it is not precluded. We're not precluded from extending the time limits. It's silent, but you are correct that we would only be seeking to extend time limits where the case so justifies. So the wording that we are proposing is that HKIAC.
啊。
嗯。
on page five.
And again, under Rule Ten, Subsection Two B.
Profession by profession, your recommendation of amendment. Thank you. Yes, thank you. I will move through page by page.
咁其實係咪應該由首席仲裁員佢都可以去做決定，定係由直情係由你哋去去做決定咧？
嗯，咁如果一方唔同意咧，覺得誒另外一方係不合理嘅要求。
before the constitution of the tribunal， it will be HKIAC。OK，嚇，即係喺喺行政嗰方面咧，就係你哋要做咗一個決定㗎啦。
嗯，但係誒喺呢啲批，譬如雙方有爭議啦，唔想延期，一方入一想需要又提供咗理由，一方咧就唔想啦，梗係啦，因為對不嚟咪可能延長咗。
由相關費，這裡我們提出要插入，如果適用，這會然後連結到權力給我們放棄。這個提出的變更是重複，也，在第8條第2B節，這是2頁上。
yes a very typical example would be the one that I expressed before where for example we receive a request from the claimant and then that is delivered to the respondent but within the 14 day period perhaps late the respondent may write to us and say we need more time to make our comments or we may hear from the legal
或respondent to say we have only just been instructed by the respondent we need more time to review the file and to come back to you with our comments in that situation we would extend the time limit a reasonable amount not to hold up the proceedings but a reasonable reasonable amount to ensure that we obtain the information.
噉嘅時候，你哋係咪就要作出一個決定嚇？噉你譬如譬如平時嚟講呢種噉嘅決定，就係要畀使唔使畀八千蚊啊？呢啲唔使啦，係嘛？呢啲唔需要㗎啦。
almost，very，very，common，very，common，so，we，make，that，decision，all，the，time。That，kind，of，procedural，decision，is，not，something，that，the，party，would，have，to，pay，for。The，party，only，needs，to，pay，the，8,000，when，they，first，lodged，their，request，for，the，appointment，of，an，arbitrator，for，a，decision，on，the，number，of，arbitrators，or，for，the，appointment，of，a，mediator。
That's correct. OK，好誒，仲有冇委員發問？如果冇咧，我哋就進入逐項審議啦，好冇啊？咁逐項審議咧就係誒，首先誒請香港國際仲裁中心協助委員開始逐項審議規定。May you help to brief um our members to follow。
on the first page, the first proposed amendment is to insert the what the words in parentheses, if applicable. This relates to the first proposed amendment with respect to the power to waive the fee. You see here that under Rule Six, Subsection Two, the request must be accompanied.
嚇！
係啦。
okay。
所以係喺頁六。
按照本條例第十條。
係講緊第十條係講緊乜嘢？
呢啲咧有冇可以提提個第十條？
好，啊，有冇委員有問題？
10 of the Hong Kong Ordinance, and then if you compare
按照本條例第十條。
因為我哋嘅法例咧係中英文版都係啊一樣生效嘅，就唔想中文版有太大嘅出入。
then if you turn to page six of your document, then you find the central change which would give effect, give HKIC power to waive the fees.
Rule 6, subsection 3A, you see that it is written that the service will be to the last known address or addresses of the other party.
Yes, thank you. So, Section 10 sets out how a party is to deliver documents to the other party. It provides that
誒，我哋都要因為有啊中文版，可能誒法律顧問亦都係啊，我哋一齊咧都要啊，我哋點樣都要睇一睇嗰個中文版嗰個對應嘅，咁所以咧，我哋有時會停一停嘅，噉樣咧就啊。
Documents will be served on the other party at the the personal address of the other party, or at the place of arbitration, or at the party's habitual residence or their mailing address. So those are the options that you have under section.
所以。
啊。
嚇，page two。
Okay, you give the discretion.
係，因為因而家有好多方式㗎啦。
係嘛？即係話證明送達咗就得㗎啦。Correct。好。
好，咁咧就係跟住係誒零零零二第。
and there you will see the inconsistency between the sub legislation and the ordinance.
which says for the purposes of subrule three, double registered post constitutes good service.
Here is the introduction of the word may instead of must. You will see that the rule provides.
The thinking behind this provision originally is that, notwithstanding that the other side does not respond, we may move forward.
Thank you. There is one other change to on page 0001, which is the deletion of rule 6 subsection 4.
我們 propose to remove that because that has raised confusion by parties as to whether or not double registered post constitute is the only way to constitute good service, which is not the case.
currently that if no information is received within 14 days after a request by HKIAC to the respondent party to the request, HKIAC must proceed to make an appointment of an arbitrator.
咁咧就誒呢個都係隨住社會改變啫，即係有唔同嘅方式去送達我哋嘅相關文件係啊認可㗎啦，喺法律上都好，我哋應住就係第二頁啦，好冇啊？就進入嗰個七配胡四係。
嗯，所以由making reference to section ten of the ordinance， we bring the sub legislation。其實係咪應該更早咧？更早就寫按照條例，因為誒unstable model law呢個憲法誒示範法係好重要。其實應該係更早做呢樣嘢嚇。OK，我冇意見嚇，改翻呢個。
however，它currently worded that we must move forward.
我們 may wish to not move forward， and I can give you an example.
put the case into abeyance. We take note of that and we do not move forward.
在那場景，我們唔會 wish to move forward with an appointment。 我們想有機會可以 hold that。
case where the case goes into abeyance and into a dark hole that no one can see. We are always in contact with the proceedings.
在那間時間，claimant writes to us and says we would like to suspend our request because we are in settlement talks with the respondent.
你都要去押判咗嗰個仲裁員，即係我瞭解下啫。夏州浩整賢問得非常之好，因為仲裁好重視嘅係程序。
在其他地方在《子法》中，它被寫成「我們可能向前走」，而我們認為「可能」更為優先，因為有幾種情況。
say you have a situation where a claimant has requested that we appoint an arbitrator. We write to the other side and we give them 14 days to submit their comments. We do not hear from them.
係係好，周浩鼎議員。誒唔該啊，主席。誒其實啊，Miss Grima解釋得好清楚嘅，因為我頭先都諗緊呢個幫點解要改翻嚟，但係又衍生咗另一個問題，我請教下。好似你頭先講嗰個scenario咁啦，嗯。
所以那係一個例子。所以呢個變動係要首先同其他法例領域對齊，特別講《規例九三》用到「可」字，而《規例十一四」，你唔見喺呢份文件入面，亦都用到「可」字。
at any time, if one of the parties would like the case to resume, then they have the power to unilaterally resume the proceedings because there the agreement for suspension has finished. So the moment a party moves us to then move forward, we move forward under the applicable rules.
原來有啲情況，可能佢話：喂，原來想又可能是哪一方想suspend想停一停咁好啦。咁按照你大家既然有噉嘅意願，噉我就唔proceed住啦嚇。我may may may wish to not proceed，噉我咪停一停咯。咁但係喺呢度，如果變如果以前寫must咧，你就見到啲時間限制就真係。
見佢一定要咁啦，但係而家因為未咧，你某程度上就嗱，因為容許佢有咗個option啊嘛，我可以延一延啦。咁但係就冇一個係咪冇一個time deadline嘅咧？即係冇一個時限嘅誒誒，即係係啦，會唔會仲有一個時限嚟？你最長只能夠延到幾時咧？我明白。
時限噉，我哋呢個酌情權去到幾多？即係如果唔係咧，大家有冇機會濫用咗呢一個誒延展又延展、延期又延期咧？即係雙方嚟講嚇，即係仲裁嘅程序係係最好重要㗎嘛嚇。Yes, great嚇。The way that we manage this kind of scenario is where the parties agree to
In terms of practicality, how do we manage the time limits? When a case is in abeyance, we provide a time limit to the parties to give us a status update as to what is happening in the case, and that way we always have a point in time at which we are seeking the parties' information as to what's going on in the proceedings, so that there there is no
得。
係。
five。
噉，噉。
有冇問題？
佢會議細B嚇。
OK，得consistency啫。
如果冇去零五啦，零五頁page。
嚇，好，咁跟住我哋落去零零零四頁第九。
again，this is the same change made again，insertion of the rule may instead of must。
啊！主席，主席一句啫，啊都好清楚嘅，即係如果係噉，都唔會話好似頭先阿Miss Kima講，我唔知去咗。
and then reference to section 10 of the Hong Kong Arbitration Ordinance and deletion of the double registered post language.
On page three, we have the repetition of the two changes that were mentioned on the first page. So the insertion of the of the words if applicable.
去咗唔知邊度咁遠，都一路唔搞，都都唔會嘅。咁純粹我只係一個問題請教下啫。誒，既然即係你哋處理好多經驗啦，通常呢啲情況，就算真係有咁發生，現下咁假設咁做啦。誒，大概係咪可能？
嚇，不過我嘅經驗都是嘅，有啲拖得好長啊。就算我自己參與嗰啲，總之大家都係拖咗好耐。啊，咁咧就誒好，咁跟住如果第二冇問題，就第三頁啦。嚇，第三頁嘅二B八。
三幾個月、半年點都應該處理到阿pond到咯。我呢個純粹一個瞭解嘅啫，合合理嘅時間嚇。Yeah, time. It depends on the case. Usually, we would put put in place a time limit of between one and three months to check in with the parties. Yeah.
是。
okay。
Capital A。
yeah you actually.
Okay, then page six.
未嘅未charge eight thousand for making。
所以，其實，係consistent。你你 keep the discretion。
The appropriate threshold would be cases under 2.5 million Hong Kong dollars.
And again, here on page five, we see the three changes that are consistent with the previous changes we've discussed.
That wording we would propose to keep as it is. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And then I can see from thirteen.
誒，我就其實都睇到咧，喺十三一嚇thirteen subsection one咧，就算係未改嘅時候，你哋用嗰個字咧都係。
頁六是 where we find the principal amendment and that is insertion insertion of reference to subrules two and the new proposed amendment two a.
proposing to do is to practice is to publish a a guideline with respect to the kinds of cases that we would consider waiving fees, and that would be measured according to the amount in dispute in the particular case. We have studied the
which is set out just below there, which says that the HKIAC may, if it considers reasonable in any particular case, waive any of the fees referred to in sub rule one. So that there is the power for us to waive fees if we consider reasonable in any particular case. For your information, what we would be
applications we have received under the ordinance between 2015 and 2018 to determine what would be an appropriate threshold, both in terms of making a meaningful contribution to to users, but also ensuring that financially speaking, the impact on HKIAC would not be of concern, and we have determined that.
啊。
誒。
Okay.
批文。
logistic.
much earlier.
Yeah, good.
Okay, yep.
We also have to update it.
Check, correct. Okay.
So then go to page seven.
Okay, then let's go to any question.
Those are repeated on pages eight and nine. Because check.
係咪？係
have answered our question here, right? I have exactly what we discussed exactly just then, yes.
頁七反映我們會引入到形式，當事人必須填寫的表格。當他們提交申請時，這些是與當事人需要勾選和通知如何繳付費用有關的非常形式化的變更。
Okay.
yes。
你覺得需要？
decision number。
用另一個表格。
表格二。
哦，好啊，好啊，好啊，得啊，你畀埋。
Okay，呃，page eight。
Okay，嗯，then is page nine。
Yeah, this is the same change. Yeah, with respect to a form three application. Yeah.
Okay, okay, good. Yes, our legal consultant has some questions.
你以前咪用表格二啊？用表格，what what form did you use? You mentioned form two.
啊！好多謝法律顧問啦，法律顧問咧就提出咧，就係喺啊一。
所以，depending on which request has been submitted, you fill in a different form. Okay, all right, yeah. So it's consistent with before. Correct, it's the same change. Yeah.
所以有三forms that are relevant. Form one is for the appointment of an arbitrator. Form two is for a decision on the number of arbitrators, and form three is for the appointment of a mediator.
This is this is the same proposed amendment to the the relevant form. So this is the form if you need a decision on the number of arbitrators, it's form two. This is the form that the party would fill in, and so there we're also amending to update with respect to payment method.
嚇。
嚇，OK，啊秘書話唔係五月廿四號，係三十一號。咁其實因為，
We've worked well with the Department of Justice with respect to the timeline that would apply, and so that we believe would be the appropriate date.
八區嘅區議會同埋兩個專業團體同埋委員咧，睇下佢哋會唔會有啊？
噉啊，睇下有冇收到書面嘅意見，我會發畀大家。再係可能你哋可以到時，如果真係有嘅，你可以補充一啲回覆畀我哋嘅。嚇，多謝大家。
嗰個規則嘅一二咧，因為你哋都係啊會係作出修訂，同埋想誒你哋解釋一下咧呢條條例，你哋希望係八月一號就生效，或者講解一下畀大家聽。
有意見嘅，噉啊，截止日期係六月八號。噉我哋委員會咧呢一度嚟講咧，我哋已經順利審議咗㗎啦。噉就睇下會唔會有任何誒書面嘅意見或者係其他嘅意見。如果收咗，我都會傳譯畀大家嘅。
Sure, thank you very much. That date is motivated by a calculation of the time that it would take for the legislation to be approved or through to pass through the process at at this body, and so with a view to
最早啦，最早可以啦。噉我覺得就誒誒法律顧問仲有冇意見？OK。咁誒秘書有冇意見？OK。頭先我一開始已經讀咗我哋嗰個時間表㗎啦，噉我就唔重複啦。噉我喺呢度咧就係誒。
要誒要問下大家委員啦，係同意呢個以上，即係我哋討論完之後咧，就係同意以上嘅誒修訂啦。噉我喺五月廿四號嗰個會咧，就係話咧，就邀請公眾就有關嘅規則誒向誒，仲有公眾喺網站咧要求十。
我哋好快開呢個會嚇，已經係盡快幫你哋盡快通過啊！三啊一號先至係成立呢個委員會排期，已經排得好快，你哋好好彩嚇。噉我諗咧就誒，暫時冇其他意見啦。啊，多謝啊，周浩鼎議員。咁多謝各位代表，我哋今日咧就係啊，宣佈散會。